# Jessica S. Jordan

Atlanta, GA 30324

Email: jsjordan79@gmail.com | Phone: 404-593-3611

LinkedIn: <a href="https://jessjordan.github.io/">www.linkedin.com/in/jessica-s-jordan/</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://jessjordan.github.io/">https://jessjordan.github.io/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

A self-motivated professional who is experienced in working in fast-paced environments that demand strong organizational, technical, and communication skills. Top performer, conscientious, highly motivated and committed to superior customer service. Detail-oriented and resourceful in completing projects; able to multi-task effectively. Experienced in supporting organization leaders, mastering new/multiple systems, and creating processes that improve efficiency and accuracy.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Tools:** Microsoft Excel, VBA, Python, Pandas, NumPy, SQL, JSON, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Beautiful Soup, JavaScript, D3.js, Plotly, Leaflet, R, Tableau, Apache Hadoop, Machine Learning, GitHub, Big

Data, Statistics

**Databases:** MongoDB, PostgreSQL **Other:** Flask, Git, Command Line

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Spotify Analysis** | Code: <a href="https://github.com/jessjordan/Spotify-Project.git">https://github.com/jessjordan/Spotify-Project.git</a>

An analysis to explore one of the most popular music streaming platforms, Spotify. Analyzed data around music popularity, artist popularity, and top user demographics. Utilized Python and Pandas to explore, import and clean data. Data updates in real-time with each call to the API that was used within the code.

Extract-Transform-Load | Code: <a href="https://github.com/jessjordan/etl-project.git">https://github.com/jessjordan/etl-project.git</a>

Using ETL to determine the most popular artists streamed by Spotify users. Data updates in real-time at the click of a button on the web page. Key tools: Python, PostgreSQL

## **US Brewery Analysis** | Code: <a href="https://github.com/jessjordan/project\_2">https://github.com/jessjordan/project\_2</a>

We will utilize data visualization to showcase breweries and to tell the story of how people unwind after a long day's work. We will be displaying this data by using API's, Datasets from Kaggle, JavaScript libraries (Leaflet, Plotly), PgAdmin PostgreSQL, as well using VS studio code. Our main concern when we show our data will be showing the breweries in the U.S. as well as showing the name of brewery, type of beer (lager, port, etc.), category of beer (Irish ale, German lager, etc.), and location (city and state).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Billing Analyst/Project Manager

Jul 2017 – Present

P.S. Energy Group, Dunwoody, GA

Generate monthly comparison and analysis of large customer accounts and data sets that include multi-transaction fueling (credit) cards and specialized billing accounts. Manage pricing analysis of Compressed Natural Gas (CNG), Unleaded, and Diesel fuels to maintain competitive pricing at Unattended Fuel Outlets (UFO stations) in the Atlanta area. Manage Emergency Fueling projects by being a direct contact to drivers in the field, reviewing dispatch trackers, driver logs, and managing the billing process from end to end.

- Reduced invoice processing time by 60% by creating SQL query to create emergency event reporting.
- Increased accuracy and efficiency by collaborating with department leaders to develop emergency fueling application for vendors and website for internal and external customers.
- Created a billing process for analyzing Natural Gas pipeline usage and meter readings to be allocated across multiple accounts.

#### Mac+ Senior Advisor

May 2015 - Jul 2017

**Apple Inc.**, Cupertino, CA

Served as a supervisor to Tier I Technical and iTunes Billing Advisors in resolving Apple account security, escalation of complex support, and safety concerns.

- Provided research of all billing issues and technical concerns.
- Assisted users with proper follow-up communications by email and phone.
- Resolved issue with unauthorized access and collaborated with developers when needed

## **Business Support Analyst**

Oct 2008 - May 2015

Sprint Communications, Atlanta, GA

Worked directly with 400+ unit, high-profile, large-revenue generating wireless business customers as single point-of-contact for issue resolution and requests regarding orders, equipment and billing. Provided detailed account reconciliation reports upon request that ensured account balance and payments were in agreement. Performed proactive research and analyzed complex information, developing and presenting innovative solutions.

- Partnered with Project Managers and sales representatives in coordinating meetings and trainings for customers.
- Saved several accounts from churning, 1 exceeding 500 units, by ensuring all network/device issues were resolved.
- Gained new business, adding 1K+ lines through skillful negotiations and retention efforts.
- Earned several awards and recognitions for consistently being a top performer.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Data Analytics | Visualization Certificate: Georgia Institute of Technology,** Atlanta, GA 2019 A 24-week intensive Boot Camp program focused on gaining technical programming skills in VBA, Python, Plotly, R, JavaScript, D3, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.